LUCCA AUGUSTO MOREIRA SANTOS

② lucca@luccaaugusto.xyz♀ Belo Horizone, MG, Brasil

github.com/luccaugusto

in linkedin.com/in/luccaugusto/

% https://dev.luccaaugusto.xyz

age 24

CAREER SUMMARY

Software Engineer with generalist skills experienced in working with agile methodologies, responsible for developing and maintaining solutions to support business, marketing and technology teams, being able to anticipate scaling problems, executive needs and developing solutions that increase autonomy of all teams, allowing for quicker changes and improvements in any part of the project. Worked mostly with Wordpress and PHP. Experience with Node.Js, React, Python, PHP, Java, Javascript, SQL, HTML, CSS, Django, C, Git, NewRelic, DevOps and AWS products.

AREAS OF EXPERIENCE

- Multidisciplinary Communication
- Web development
- Agile Methodologies
- Software Engineering
- Growth Hacking
- Startups, Edutech and Fintech
- Digital Products
- Analytical and Systemic View
- SEO

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Software Engineer

City Shoppe (https://cityshoppe.com)

🛗 June 2021 - April 2023

Austin-TX, US (remote)

CityShoppe is a digital marketplace startup for small businesses in the US and Europe.

As the second person in the dev team i was responsible for understanding everything about the business and tech stack, as well as participating in all the software decisions and solutions finding. I also helped hands on building all the company's products, developing key features and setting up infrastructure to make it reliable and available. These efforts resulted in raising over 200 thousand dollars in investment for the company. Most of the project was built in Wordpress before we moved to a NestJS application.

- Worked with people from 4 different countries in one project, further developing my communication skills
- Developed products in NodeJS, NestJS and PHP, using AWS services (lambda, API gateway, ECS, EC2, etc) for infrastructure.

Full Stack Software Engineer

Educando Seu Bolso (https://educandoseubolso.blog.br)

August 2017 - January 2019 / August 2019 - June 2020

Financial Edutech that connects companies and people through courses, podcasts and tools. Business model through affiliate programs and digital products.

I joined the team as a intern and was responsible for understanding the business from a tech perspective and helping build the business tools. I quickly demonstrated skills of communication and product development, and was later hired. I built a platform in Django to manage all our data and improve our tools, increasing efficiency for the marketing, commercial and technology teams, as well as allowing for the business to grow faster. Developed strong communication skills as this job required constant communication with the commercial team to translate the idea into a user friendly tool.

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

Machine Languages

C Java Python PHP Javascript

TypeScript POSIX Shell

Human Languages

English (fluent)
Portuguese (native)
Spanish (conversational)
Japanese (basic)



TECH SKILLS

Wordpress
SQL
Shell script
Linux
HTML
CSS
Git
React
Django
Node

AWS



SOFT SKILLS

Communication Creativity

Multitasking Organization

EDUCATION

Certificate in Administration SEBRAE contagem

2014 - 2016

Bachelors Degree in Computer Science

PUC Minas

2017 - 2021